It was the first time meeting.
NOTE inferred from surrounding cues
And I never knew what was going to happen.
NOTE title card
One Moment.
I'm Taro Kevin Nordberg.
I grew up in Japan.
My mother is from Kyoto. My father is Swiss.
NOTE inferred from surrounding cues
I was born into a calligraphist and sumi-e painting family.
Fourth generation now.
NOTE inferred from surrounding cues
Mr The place we are today is called Daikaku-ji.
It's one of the most holy places here in Kyoto.
was thinking about this place for a
NOTE inferred from surrounding cues
Why are we here?
I was approached by Mark Greenslade
to put together a team of people
NOTE inferred from surrounding cues
and to create a unique performance
and capture the moment.
NOTE confirmed by the producer
I wanted to do something that was without compromise.
And create a space,
NOTE confirmed by the producer
a very special space with no constraints at all
upon the artistic expression.
NOTE confirmed by the producer
I was very much attracted
to the idea of a performance in which
NOTE confirmed by the producer
the moment was quintessential,
the absolute moment of the performance.
I was very close always with jazz and live music.
I always felt there's a big harmony between
creating art pieces whilst listening to music.
I had the privilege to bring Jason, Akira and Kazu here,
in my hometown,
lot of blissful happiness.
With these guys, I wanna do a project
and a very special story to be born.
As a jazz musician, it's pretty customary
NOTE inferred from surrounding cues
to be thrown into
these different situations.
In fact, I feel like I thrive in that. I
really get excited about the unknown.
From my understanding, it was going to be
performance-based in a way that the
painting was going to be the main theme.
And then we're going to be accompanying that.
But it was much more collaborative
than I thought it was.
We would play some music, it prompted
Kevin on how to react
to us, and vice versa.
I was definitely curious, I've never
performed live, with an artist painting
live in any setting.
Musically, I was quite intrigued as to
what was going to happen, given that the
NOTE inferred from surrounding cues
musicians I had never met before,
and then also playing in a setting that's
NOTE inferred from surrounding cues
new for all of us, I think just
heightened the experience.
NOTE inferred from surrounding cues
I'm not really familiar with jazz music,
so I didn't know what kind of sounds to use.
My playing is more about receiving impressions directly from nature,
NOTE inferred from surrounding cues
and at that moment, I don't even know what kind of sound I want to make,
But when I play the sounds that come naturally to me at that moment,
the others seem to fit perfectly with what I'm playing.
NOTE inferred from surrounding cues
I feel really grateful to have met and been able to play with such great musicians
It was just absolutely incredible to see
this harmony between the three musicians,
although it is so different,
the genre between piano and the guitar,
and the shinobi, the bamboo flute.
But it's in universal language, and we
just got so influenced by the surroundings,
with the birds chirping,
hearing the water, the koi fishes, and
also this absolutely magnificent tea house, with this view.
NOTE matched (smoothed against own best)
I naturally felt the vibrations of the piano and guitar, and
I felt as if the wind was weaving.
NOTE matched (smoothed against own best)
Then, before I knew it, Taro was drawing the flow of the wind,
NOTE inferred from surrounding cues
When I looked, I felt like it had been born.
I never know what's going to happen on
the canvas, I always let
myself inspire at the very moment.
We did a bit of a tour, and I know some of the priests,
and they told us that
Daikakuji is actually protected by a huge dragon,
which is floating, apparently, above the pond.
And there was just a magical moment, I
just, I lost the
NOTE inferred from surrounding cues
feeling for time and space,
and with the help of those magnificent musicians,
Kazu, Akira, and Jason,
we became all one for those 40 minutes
I found it to be deeply, deeply moving,
that it sort of accessed parts of myself
NOTE inferred from surrounding cues
that I didn't really know
existed until I was in that moment.
And just also being consciously aware of
the present moment, but also being deeply
sort of respectful of the hundreds and
hundreds of years that have gone before.
And I just sort of felt that it all
tied into that moment.
To be totally honest, I was overcome with
emotion at the very beginning.
I had to keep myself in check so that I
didn't go out of control.
Kevin really stressed the fact that
he really wanted us to exhibit our inner feelings.
And don't be shy about
putting it out on the table.
It really was apparent in a way that I
was not expecting this time around.
NOTE inferred from surrounding cues
So it was a unique and
extraordinary experience.
Today, especially in this wonderful atmosphere of the Daikaku-ji,
I was able to play with wonderful artists, and
And Taro-kun gave that to me in the form of a dragon, and.
It truly became a performance that I will never forget in my life
I was born and raised near Arashiyama
I always went to kindergarten in Saga, and sometimes my grandfather would come and pick me up, and
NOTE confirmed by the producer
we would pass by here near Saga Island, go around Hiroyama Pond
Even though my grandfather passed away a long time ago, every year when I return to Kyoto for the Saga festival,
NOTE inferred from surrounding cues
I always make sure to come back here and ride the Charenko, feeling the familiar space, and
I've always wanted to perform live at Daikakuin Temple
NOTE inferred from surrounding cues
and today, for the first time, with Jason, Akira, and Kazu,
I was able to give a live performance that I'll never forget.